<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.2//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.2/docbookx.dtd">
<article>
  <title>ModuleName 3.0 Manual</title>

  <para>Welcome to the ModuleName Manual. This document will aid you in
  setting up and running ModuleName on your IRC network.</para>

  <para>&lt;add module introduction&gt;</para>

  <para>ModuleName is Copyright, 2006 by Justin Hammond.</para>

  <sect1>
    <title>Prerequisites and Installation.</title>

    <para>ModuleName is designed to run on Top of NeoStats. The Following
    requirements at the time of writing are required for
    NeoStats:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>A Linux or BSD based Server or Shell.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>A IRCd supported by NeoStats. See the <link
          linkend="???">NeoStats</link> website.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Some basic Unix administration Skill</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Of Course, a IRC network to connect it all together.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>

    <para>Please refer to the NeoStats website for more information on the
    requirements</para>

    <para>ModuleName itself requires the following:<itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>NeoStats 3.0 or Higher correctly installed and Running</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>The time to read this entire document. </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>

    <sect2>
      <title>Compiling and Installation</title>

      <para>As long as you have successfully setup NeoStats, and installed it
      correctly, Compiling ModuleName is very simple and straight forward.
      First you must extract the files from the download package. This is as
      simple as:</para>

      <screen>bash$<command> tar -xzf ModuleName-&lt;ver&gt;.tar.gz</command></screen>

      <para>This should then create a directory called
      ModuleName-&lt;version&gt; where &lt;version&gt; is the Version of
      ModuleName. Then Proceed to Change into the ModuleName directory, and
      run Configure as follows:<screen>bash$<command>./configure [--enable-debug | --with-neostats=&lt;dir&gt;]</command></screen></para>

      <para>--enable-debug is only useful for diagnostics purposes when used
      in conjunction with debugging tools. There should be no need to use this
      option on a day to day basis</para>

      <para>--with-neostats=&lt;dir&gt; should be used if your neostats
      directory is not in a standard location (~/NeoStats/). Replace
      &lt;dir&gt; with the full path to your NeoStats installation directory
      (NOT SOURCE DIRECTORY)</para>

      <para>Configuring ModuleName will look something like the following
      screen:</para>

      <screen>Fishs-Mac:~/Documents/Dev/ModuleName justin$ ./configure       
checking whether to enable maintainer-specific portions of Makefiles... no
checking for a BSD-compatible install... /usr/bin/install -c
checking whether build environment is sane... yes
checking for gawk... no
checking for mawk... no
checking for nawk... no

&lt;snip&gt;

checking To Enable AutoTools Debug Mode?... no
checking silent building of source files... Enabled
configure: creating ./config.status
config.status: creating Makefile
config.status: creating modconfig.h
config.status: modconfig.h is unchanged
config.status: executing depfiles commands
Configuration complete.
Press Enter key to read the release notes</screen>

      <para>The Configure process will then prompt you to read the release
      notes. You are encouraged to read this document throughly as it might
      contain important information about the current version of ModuleName
      that isn't covered in the manual.</para>

      <para>If the configuration did not produce a error, you may then move
      onto Compiling ModuleName. Compiling is simply just issuing the "make"
      command (or "gmake" if you are running BSD):</para>

      <screen>Fishs-Mac:~/Documents/Dev/ModuleName justin$ make
make -s all-am
Compiling Helpers.c:                                                  [OK]     
Compiling ModuleName.c:                                               [OK]     
Compiling scan.c:                                                     [OK]     
Compiling OnJoinBot.c:                                                [OK]     
Compiling ModuleName_help.c:                                          [OK]     
Compiling update.c:                                                   [OK] </screen>

      <para>Again, check for Error messages. As long as there are not error
      messages, "make install" will install ModuleName, this README file, and
      any auxiliary files needed into your NeoStats directory:</para>

      <screen>Fishs-Mac:~/Documents/Dev/ModuleName justin$ make install
Installing ModuleName.so:                                             [OK]     
Installing viri.dat:                                                  [OK]     
Installing README.ModuleName:                                         [OK]     
Installing README.ModuleName.html:                                    [OK] </screen>

      <para>If you receive *ANY* errors at all during the this process, please
      post them on our Support boards, at
      http//www.neostats.net/boards/</para>

      <para>Once Installation is complete, you can either configure NeoStats
      to load ModuleName when it starts, or load ModuleName via IRC.</para>

      <para>To Configure NeoStats to automatically load ModuleName when it
      boots, modify the neostats.conf file and add ModuleName to the list of
      modules to load:</para>

      <screen>MODULENAME = {
       "statserv",
       "hostserv",
       "ModuleName",
} </screen>

      <para>To load ModuleName via IRC, you must make sure you have the
      appropriate permissions and issue the following command:</para>

      <para><command>/msg neostats load ModuleName</command></para>

      <para>Thats it. ModuleName is now loaded and ready for use (in fact, it
      will already be running now, but read on for further
      information.)</para>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>

  <sect1>
    <title>Basic Configuration</title>

    <para>ModuleName is completely configured online via IRC. When you first
    start up ModuleName, it attempts some "Sane" defaults for you get started
    with, but you should always review these settings as soon as you install.
    There are a few important settings you may want to review right away. They
    are:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>blah blah</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>blah blah</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>blah blah</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>These are outlined below:</para>

    <sect2>
      <title>Blah Blah</title>

      <para>Blah Blah</para>
    </sect2>

    <sect2>
      <title>Blah Blah</title>

      <para>BLAH BLAH</para>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>

  <sect1>
    <title>Detailed Configuration</title>

    <para>ModuleName attempts to be as configurable as possible in order to
    cater for each individual networks requirements. This in turn though makes
    the configuration very complex. There are many many settings with
    ModuleName that affect how it operates, how it responds and even, how
    affects the performance of NeoStats Overall. Out of the box, ModuleName
    provides sensible defaults for these settings, but you may wish to read
    this section for details on exactly what each option does, and its affect
    on how ModuleName operates.</para>

    <para>The following list summaries the available options you can set in
    ModuleName</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>NICK</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>ALTNICK</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>USER</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>HOST</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>REALNAME</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>EXCLUSIONS</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>BLAHBLAH</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>To change any of these settings, you use the Set Interface in
    ModuleName. Eg:</para>

    <screen>/msg ModuleName set &lt;option&gt; &lt;params&gt;</screen>

    <para>To view the current settings, issue the following command:</para>

    <screen>/msg ModuleName set list</screen>

    <para>The following Sections describes the different options, their
    params, and the effect on ModuleName in detail.</para>

    <sect2>
      <title>NICK Setting</title>

      <para>This setting allows you to change the Nickname that ModuleName
      uses when it connects to your network. If you change this setting make
      sure you update your NeoNet account, otherwise you might loose access to
      the Secure IRC-Chat site if we perform a check on your network and can't
      find "ModuleName" running.</para>

      <warning>
        <para>This option requires you to reload ModuleName or restart
        NeoStats to take effect.</para>
      </warning>

      <screen>/msg ModuleName set NICK &lt;nickname&gt;</screen>
    </sect2>

    <sect2>
      <title>ALTNICK Setting</title>

      <para>This setting allows you to set a "Backup" nickname used for
      ModuleName. If the primary Nickname in the NICK Setting is not
      available, ModuleName will use this nickname, and if that is not
      available, it will use a automatically generated nickname</para>

      <warning>
        <para>This option requires you to reload ModuleName or restart
        NeoStats to take effect</para>
      </warning>

      <screen>/msg ModuleName set ALTNICK &lt;nickname&gt;</screen>
    </sect2>

    <sect2>
      <title>USER Setting</title>

      <para>This option allows you to customize the "user" or ident portion of
      the ModuleName Bot. </para>

      <warning>
        <para>This option requires you to reload ModuleName or restart
        NeoStats to take effect</para>
      </warning>

      <screen>/msg ModuleName set USER &lt;user&gt;</screen>
    </sect2>

    <sect2>
      <title>HOST Setting</title>

      <para>This option allows you to customize the Hostname that ModuleName
      uses when it signs onto your Network. It defaults to the Standard
      Hostname specified in your NeoStats configuration.</para>

      <warning>
        <para>This option requires you to reload ModuleName or restart
        NeoStats to take effect</para>
      </warning>

      <screen>/msg ModuleName set HOST &lt;host&gt;</screen>
    </sect2>

    <sect2>
      <title>REALNAME Setting</title>

      <para>This option allows you to customize the realname (or Gecos) that
      ModuleName uses when it signs onto your Network. </para>

      <warning>
        <para>This option requires you to reload ModuleName or restart
        NeoStats to take effect</para>
      </warning>

      <screen>/msg ModuleName set REALNAME &lt;realname&gt;</screen>
    </sect2>

    <sect2>
      <title>EXCLUSIONS Setting</title>

      <para>This option enables ModuleName to use the Global Exclusions list
      that is control by the main NeoStats bot. This allows you to maintain a
      "global" exclusion list that is applicable to all modules in NeoStats,
      and then only apply individual exclusions to ModuleName. </para>

      <warning>
        <para>This option only becomes effective on new users joining your
        Network. Existing users that are already connected when you enable
        this option will not be rescanned for exclusions, as the Global
        Exclusions are only effected when a new user signs onto the Network.
        In order to make the global exclusions list effective straight away,
        you should restart NeoStats.</para>
      </warning>

      <para>If you wish to enable or disable the Global Exclusions lists,
      issue the following command</para>

      <screen>/msg ModuleName set EXCLUSIONS &lt;ON/OFF&gt;</screen>
    </sect2>

    <sect2>
      <title>BLAH Blah Setting</title>

      <para>blah blah description</para>

      <para>To Change the setting, issue the following Command:</para>

      <screen>/msg ModuleName set blahblah &lt;blah&gt; </screen>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>

  <sect1>
    <title>Operational Commands</title>

    <para>ModuleName has a number of commands that you can issue it in order
    to perform checks or operations on your IRC network. These commands aid
    Administrators in keeping their network secure, and keeping ModuleName
    upto date.</para>

    <para>The following list summarizes these commands:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>HELP</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>VERSION</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>ABOUT</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>CREDITS</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>LEVELS</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>SET</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>EXCLUDE</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>BLAHBLAH</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>The following Sections Describe these commands in detail</para>

    <sect2>
      <title>HELP Command</title>

      <para>The help command allows the users to access the online help for
      the different commands available. You can get general help about the
      available commands, or can access more specific information about a
      command.</para>

      <para>To see the help pages, use the following format:</para>

      <screen>/msg ModuleName help [command]
</screen>

      <para>command is optional and only required if you want more specific
      information about a particular command</para>
    </sect2>

    <sect2>
      <title>VERSION Command</title>

      <para>This command displays the Version of ModuleName, and the dat
      files. </para>

      <para>The format of the command is as follows:</para>

      <screen>/msg ModuleName version
</screen>
    </sect2>

    <sect2>
      <title>ABOUT Command</title>

      <para>The about command shows a brief description of the Bot and its
      purpose.</para>

      <para>The format of the command is as follows:</para>

      <screen>/msg ModuleName about
</screen>
    </sect2>

    <sect2>
      <title>CREDITS Command</title>

      <para>The credits command shows details about the authors or
      contributors of to the Module</para>

      <para>The format of the command is as follows:</para>

      <screen>/msg ModuleName credits
</screen>
    </sect2>

    <sect2>
      <title>LEVELS Command</title>

      <para>The levels command allows you to adjust the security of each
      command available in this module. You can make certian commands only
      available to higher "level" users in NeoStats. </para>

      <para>For more information about NeoStats Levels and Security, please
      consult the NeoStats Manual</para>

      <para>To list the currently configured levels, issue the following
      command:</para>

      <screen>/msg ModuleName levels list
</screen>

      <para>To change the minimum level required to execute a command, issue
      the following command:</para>

      <screen>/msg ModuleName levels &lt;command&gt; &lt;level&gt;</screen>

      <para>Where:</para>

      <para>command = is the actual command name you wish to modify</para>

      <para>level = a number between 0 and 200 that specifies the new
      level.</para>
    </sect2>

    <sect2>
      <title>SET Command</title>

      <para>The set command allows you to modify settings applicable to this
      module. For a complete description of the available set options, please
      consult the Detailed Configuration Section of this manual.</para>
    </sect2>

    <sect2>
      <title>EXCLUDE Command</title>

      <para>Exclusion lists allow you to specify certain Hostmasks, Servers,
      or Channels that should be excluded from monitoring by ModuleName. This
      exclusion list would allow a administrator to say, allow users on that
      are matched against Trojans, when the administrator has verified that
      the Trojan does not in fact exist on the users host.</para>

      <caution>
        <para>Exclusions should be setup for your Services Server, so that
        ModuleName does not try to scan ChanServ, or NickServ, or any of the
        bots relating to Nickname protection.</para>
      </caution>

      <para>With NeoStats 3.0, you should also be aware that there are two
      types of Exclusion Lists. There are "Global" exclusion lists that all
      modules may optionally use, and there is module specific exclusion
      lists. ModuleName defaults to not using the Global Exclusion lists. You
      can enable it by the following command:<screen>/msg ModuleName set exclusions on</screen></para>

      <para><emphasis role="bold">Adding a Entry</emphasis></para>

      <para>To add a entry to the Exclusion list, use the following
      format:</para>

      <screen>/msg ModuleName exclude add &lt;host/Server/Channel/UserHost&gt; &lt;pattern&gt; &lt;reason&gt;</screen>

      <para>Where:</para>

      <para>&lt;Host/Server/Channel/UserHost&gt; = The type of exclusion you
      are adding. The different types are:<itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Host - The Users real (Internet) Hostname</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Server - The Users server they are connecting to. You should
            ensure you add a exclusion for your Services Server</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Channel - A specific channel on your IRC Network</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>UserHost - The users Virtual Hostname (IRC)</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>

      <para>&lt;pattern&gt; = The pattern you wish to match on. May include
      wildcard charactors such as * and ?</para>

      <para>&lt;reason&gt; = a short description of the exclusion, for
      operator reference only.</para>

      <para>The output is as follows:</para>

      <screen>[13:20] -ModuleName- Added *.blah.com (userhost) to exclusion list
[13:20] ModuleName Fish added *.blah.com (userhost) to the exclusion list</screen>

      <para><emphasis role="bold">Listing an Entry</emphasis></para>

      <para>To list the Exclusions simple type:</para>

      <screen>/msg ModuleName exclude list</screen>

      <para>And all the current exclusions are listed. Additionally, a
      Position number is provided for use with the delete command. The output
      is as follows:</para>

      <screen>[13:21]  -ModuleName- Exclusion list:
[13:21]  -ModuleName- #bothouse (Channel) Added by Fish on Sat Aug 13 2005 01:20 AM SGT for Requested
[13:21]  -ModuleName- #ircop (Channel) Added by Fish on Sat Aug 13 2005 07:40 PM SGT for IRCop channel
[13:21]  -ModuleName- *irc-chat.net (Host) Added by Fish on Tue Aug 09 2005 10:13 PM SGT for Services Exclusion
[13:21]  -ModuleName- chieftess!*@* (Userhost) Added by Fish on Tue Aug 09 2005 10:14 PM SGT for buggy client
[13:21]  -ModuleName- *.blah.com (Userhost) Added by Fish on Sun Jan 15 2006 01:20 PM SGT for Cause Blah.com is cool
[13:21]  -ModuleName- End of list.</screen>

      <para><emphasis role="bold">Deleting an Entry</emphasis></para>

      <para>To delete a entry, you should first lookup the Position of the
      entry that you wish to delete. The format of the command is as
      follows:</para>

      <screen>/msg ModuleName exclude del &lt;pattern&gt;</screen>

      <para>Where:</para>

      <para>&lt;pattern&gt; is the pattern of the entry you wish to delete in
      the list</para>

      <para>The output of the command is as follows:</para>

      <screen>[13:22]  ModuleName Fish used EXCLUDE
[13:22]  -ModuleName- *.blah.com delete from exclusion list</screen>
    </sect2>

    <sect2>
      <title>BLAHBLAH Command</title>

      <para>That command forces ModuleName to check the Dat File version at
      <link linkend="???">http://secure.irc-chat.net/</link> and download the
      latest version if required.</para>

      <warning>
        <para>Repeated use of this command in a short period of time will
        result in your account at secure.irc-chat.net being suspended for
        abuse. Use with CARE</para>
      </warning>

      <para>The format of the command is as follows:</para>

      <screen>/msg ModuleName update</screen>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>

  <sect1>
    <title>Optional Chapter</title>

    <para>use this to write any optional information etc etc etc</para>

    <sect2>
      <title>Optional Sub Heading</title>

      <para>Subheading</para>

      <sect3>
        <title>Minor heading</title>

        <para>minor heading</para>
      </sect3>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>
</article>
